# Dominic J Mitchell

Front End Web Designer & Developer 1-401-440-3243 Providence, RI Area

dominic.joseph.mitchell.2018@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dominic-j-mitchell

https://github.com/DominicJosephMitchell

Full Stack developer, specializing in front end web design UI/UX. Outgoing, enthusiastic business professional who is a technophile, cyberjunkie. Why I enjoy tech: The drive to succeed, the passion for learning, developing new of skills, and the gaining of knowledge. "The world of programming is never ending. New technologies are constantly being crafted and we, as developers, need to keep up with such an advance or we will be left behind.." Graduate of: (IEL) Institute of Entrepreneurial & Leadership, Rhode Coders Web Development, and (GA) General Assembly. With 30 years experience in construction, management, & 8 years technology skills.

**Employment History** 

Web Design & Developer Fellow GA – General Assembly 10/2018-present

\*Twelve week web development immersive program (600hrs plus)

Advanced Support Center Engineer I Cox Communications 01/2013-06/2018

\*Lead and trainer, tester new deployments, procedure development, voice, data, video support, networking

Applications Specialist – III Lead/Trainer Up-Source 01/2012-12/2012

\*Supporting 3<sup>rd</sup> party software and hardware applications: troubleshooting, break fix, install.

Consultant/Tech TMC 11/2010-01/2012

\*Advice and expertise: management, structure and strategy, IT, marketing, design, build-outs.

Founder / Entrepreneur Mitchell Construction Inc 04/2004-11/2010

\*Design/development, sales, consulting, marketing strategies, Project Management, Leadership.

#### **Education**

Institute – of – Entrepreneurial & Leadership

2018

2011

\*HTML – CSS – JavaScript V
New Horizons Computer Learning Center

Web Design & Development

\*A+, Net+, Sec+, MCP&MCDST Network Support Technician Community

College of Rhode Island 2003

\*Associates in Arts Degree

## **Technical Skills**

Proficient:

HTML, CSS, wire-frames, Bootstrap, Scrum/Agile, Git-Hub, Bash, express.js,

React, JavaScript, Mongoose, MongoDB

#### Familiar:

Handlebars, AWS, Ruby on Rails, SQL back-end API's, SASS, Ajax, jQuery JSON, Node.js

### Web Development Projects https://dominicjosephmitchell.github.io/DJMPortfolio/

\*Bucket List: Things you'd love to do with your life, Let's get 'em on paper! Integrate with a third-party location-based API to allow users to search for a location or venue to add to their bucket list items.

(using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Leaflet (map), Ajax, MongoDB, Mongoose and express.js)

- \*Trails: Welcome to Southern New England Trails, create an index of the trails that you have experienced. (using HTML/CSS/React//MongoDB/Mongoose, and express.js)
- \* Tic Tac Toe: A custom front-end JavaScript game engine which connects with a third-party API.
- \* Vacations: Multi-page user experience designed photo album for your viewing pleasure. (using HTML, CSS)
- \* Family Tree: Ancestry database for creation and storing of family data. Add your family tree. (using HTML, CSS, JavaScript)